<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: xcode | MacOps.io]]></title>
  <link href="http://macops.github.io/blog/categories/xcode/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://macops.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-31T21:41:26+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://macops.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[headmin]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[info+blog@macop.io]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MacMini as Main Dev Machine]]></title>
    <link href="http://macops.github.io/macmini/dev/xcode/2013/05/31/macmini-as-main-dev-machine/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-31T00:25:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://macops.github.io/macmini/dev/xcode/2013/05/31/macmini-as-main-dev-machine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just to share how to setup a pretty fast and reliable developer machine, a Apple MacMini Server QuadCore i7 .
The box will be based on a FusionDrive setup, no extra skills required appart following the iFixIt tutorial, the average turnaround time to have the box ready will be 45 minutes, you&rsquo;ll need a torx and a 3rd party SSD replacement drive as extra parts besides the MacMini Server (or normal MacMini with OWC DataDoubler Kit).
Thus far I&rsquo;ve only tried this two times, everytime I&rsquo;ve used an unbooted mini but see no problem to start such set up anytime later on any Thunderbolt MacMini (the data on remaining harddrive on the MacMini Server will be destroyed though &ndash; so be backed up)</p>

<ol>
<li>get a MacMini Server with i7 Processor</li>
<li>turn upside down, open the cover</li>
<li>follow instuctions to replace the hard drive for from the mini: <a href="http://bit.ly/18A62NA">http://bit.ly/18A62NA</a></li>
<li>replace the drive with a decent SSD</li>
<li>finish the instructions above but don&rsquo;t boot yet</li>
<li>connect the exctracted hard drive via external USB case to the mini</li>
<li>boot from the external USB</li>
<li>go thru OS X setup assistant as usual, create a account</li>
<li>login to the account</li>
<li>now you&rsquo;ll see that diskutility tells you there is a problem with the drive</li>
<li>diskutility offers to fix the problem for you</li>
</ol>


<p>&hellip; et Voila!<br/>
You&rsquo;ll get automagically build a FusionDrive by OS X Mountain Lion for free, without mumbling in the Terminal at all so we&rsquo;re following the koan &lsquo;less code is better code&rsquo; and on top you&rsquo;ll save some code kittens for more important tasks &ndash; pretty cool isn&rsquo;t it ?</p>

<p>To finish things up transfer some user data, install Xcode and your other dev tools required &ndash; you&rsquo;ll have a decent
fast machine in about two hours ready for any development task.
best not forget to upgrade RAM to 16GB and you&rsquo;re ready to run at top speed at a unbeatable price.</p>

<h3>Final Specs:</h3>

<ul>
<li>MacMini 2.6 GHz Intel i7 QuadCore</li>
<li>16 GB Ram</li>
<li>1,5 TB Fusion drive</li>
</ul>


<p>will cost about roughly:</p>

<h3>€1461  / $1461</h3>

<p>some parts I&rsquo;ve used to build the two boxes</p>

<ul>
<li>16 GB Ram &ndash; <a href="http://amzn.to/ZxxoB0">http://amzn.to/ZxxoB0</a></li>
<li>SSD drive &ndash; <a href="http://amzn.to/18BrHVM">http://amzn.to/18BrHVM</a>  / <a href="http://amzn.to/116fEHk">http://amzn.to/116fEHk</a></li>
</ul>


<p>in case you already have a MacMini but not a Server version, this kit will enable any Thunderbolt based MacMini to run a second drive:</p>

<ul>
<li>OWC DataDoubler &ndash; <a href="http://amzn.to/14db7Vp">http://amzn.to/14db7Vp</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
